(chill music)
- [Cristian] Hello everyone.
This is Professor Cristian Lopez Vargas,
and in this video we're going to discuss
what is microeconomics
and what is the structure of this course.
So, what is microeconomics?
Microeconomics is mainly the
study of individual behavior.
Individual behavior can
refer to one person,
for example, one consumer,
or it can refer to the
behavior of one firm,
one company, for example.
Microeconomics also studies
how consumers aggregate
or form together what
we call the demand side,
and similarly, microeconomics also studies
how firms or companies together form
what we call the supply side.
The supply side and the
demand side come together
and operate in what we call a market.
And markets can take different structures,
and shapes, and features,
and there are markets
that are more competitive.
There are some types of markets
that we call perfectly competitive.
And there are other types of markets
that are less competitive
or more monopolistic.
In that other extreme we
have monopolies, of course,
where the market is
served by only one agent,
and there are other markets that are,
that operate under an oligopoly,
which means that fewer firms
are serving the market.
Microeconomics also studies
what we call game theory.
Game theory is a study of
situations that we call strategic.
Strategic situations are those situations
in which what my opponent or
my competitor does affects me,
and therefore, when I decide
to choose my best action,
I need to consider what the other person,
or the other opponent,
or the competitor firm
will do as well.
Finally, microeconomics also studies
what we call market failures.
Market failures arise
when information is
asymmetrically distributed
among economic agents,
or when there exists something
that we call externalities.
Let us briefly discuss what is
the structure of this course.
First, we will discuss what
we call consumer theory.
Consumer theory is everything
related to the consumer,
meaning how his preferences
and constraints come together
and form what we call the optimal bundle.
And how, collectively, consumers aggregate
into what we call the demand side.
Then we will discuss what
we call producer theory.
Producer theory is everything
related to the firm,
including its cost, its technology,
how the firm finds the optimal bundle,
and how multiple firms aggregate
into what we call the supply side.
Then we will discuss markets.
Markets can be competitive,
which happens when,
for example, we have many
firms, and many consumers,
and information flows freely.
And markets can also have other structures
in which there is market power.
Market power is what we call,
is a situation where
one firm, for example,
has power of one side of the market.
One simple example is a monopoly.
In a monopoly, only one
firm serves the whole market
and therefore has market
power because of that.
Finally, we will discuss game theory,
and as I mentioned before,
game theory is the study
of strategic interactions.
(chill music)